<u>Harsh Mohan Gajra</u>

McLean, VA,USA 20151 | 6073388922 | harsh.gajra@gmail.com

Objective

Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience specializing in Software Development using Java frameworks like Jersey RESTful Web Services, Spring Boot ,Hibernate and AWS . Possesses a MS in Computer Science from State University of New York, impeccable problem solving and software engineering skills, and excellent interpersonal skills. Looking for a challenging and interesting role in Software Development. I was core part of Software engineering team at Pype Inc , a Construction SaaS company (Acquired by AutoDesk).

Education

Master's in Computer Science - State University Of New York, Binghamton, August 2016 - May 2018 Bachelor of Computer Engineering - K.J.Somaiya College of Engineering, Mumbai, First class

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Database Systems, Operating Systems, Object Oriented

Programming Languages, Design Patterns.

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/harsh-gajra/ **GitHub**: https://github.com/HarshGajraSUNY

Work Experience

Software Developer 2 – FINRA | Reston, VA, USA , May 2020-Present

- Contributed to design and development of test automation suites to make REST- API calls and compare the response data against date pulled by SQL query output using Junit, Java, Postgres.
- Contributed to the design and development of functionality to enhance the features of Finra's Consolidated Audit Trail project using technologies like Java, AWS stack consisting of Cloud Formation, Lambda, EC2 and S3.
- Wrote SQL queries using Postgres on Amazon RDS to pull the required data to develop reports relating to
 Equities and Options traded on various stock exchanges that were displayed for the Finra's Consolidated Audit
 Trail Project dashboards for its Accuracy.
- Prioritize the team's development work ,created user stories and issues on JIRA , configured and developed the
 queries in Jira Query Language to search for particular issues matching a given predicate on Atlassian Jira Project
 Tracking Software.

Software Engineer - Pype Inc | Herndon, VA, USA , July 2018 - June 2020

- Backend software engineering, design and Development of new features using microservices for web applications using Java 8, Jersey JAX-RS REST api framework, Spring Boot, and MySQL as the database.
- Designing and developed internal software solutions for optimizing the business process followed by in-house Sales and Support teams thus saving the organization \$360,000 per year in costs and 15,000 man-hours per year.
- Full Stack development of a document management and turnover package software application using Angular 6,Html, css on frontend (20%) and Java 8, Jersey REST API framework on backend (80%) and MySql as database.
- Designed the data model and developed the backend code for an Email Cadence software tool using Java 8, Spring Boot, JPA and MySQL database.
- Experienced in using the message brokers like RabbitMQ for message queuing and asynchronous job processing.
- Managed, mentored and gave work assignments and conducted code reviews for junior software engineers.
- Algorithm Development: Design, Analyze and implement algorithms in core Java for solving various use cases across the software products of the company.
- · Writing integrations of current applications with externals cloud services e.g AWS S3.
- Production support of Applications: Provided L3 Production support for company's software products.
- Develop, implement and/or improve the application production support knowledge management repository to ensure all are documented, process & procedures are clear and periodic reviews are conducted.
- DevOps: Create and maintain fully automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment using Jenkins and GitLab.
- Researching and development of proof of concepts for new product development using Google cloud console, AWS, GIMP and Java 8.
- Writing automations for the manual tasks performed by Customer Support and Success Teams within the company's software products.

Technical Skills

Java 8 **Data Structures Eclipse** Angular 6 Amazon Web Services REST api GitHub Gradle Jenkins CI/CD Spring Boot Jira JPA MySQL Android ΑPI **GIMP** Prototyping

Proof of Concepts Web Applications Design Patterns

CSS Maven Glassfish Framework Cloud **HTML** JAX-RS Junit JavaScript Postgres Restful **NoSQL** Software Development UI Node.js IDE DynamoDB J2ee NetBeans SQL Code Review Java Software Development PL/SQL GUI **JDBC** Microservices

Paper Publications

• Paper: Credit card Fraud Detection and Prevention Using Perceptron Training Algorithm.

Journal: International Journal on Recent and Innovation Trends in Computing and Communication, Apr 2015

Link: https://ijritcc.org/index.php/ijritcc/article/view/4182/4182